<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!--
  SPDX-FileCopyrightText: none
  SPDX-License-Identifier: CC0-1.0
-->
<component type="desktop">
  <id>org.kde.marble.behaim.desktop</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>LGPL-2.1-or-later</project_license>
  <name>Behaim Globe</name>
  <name xml:lang="bg">Глобус на Бехайм</name>
  <name xml:lang="ca">Globus terraqüi de Behaim</name>
  <name xml:lang="ca-valencia">Globus terraqüi de Behaim</name>
  <name xml:lang="cs">Behaimův globus</name>
  <name xml:lang="de">Behaim-Globus</name>
  <name xml:lang="en-GB">Behaim Globe</name>
  <name xml:lang="eo">Behaim-Globo</name>
  <name xml:lang="es">Globo de Behaim</name>
  <name xml:lang="eu">Behaim Globoa</name>
  <name xml:lang="fi">Behaimin karttapallo</name>
  <name xml:lang="fr">Behaim Globe</name>
  <name xml:lang="gl">Globo terráqueo de Behaim</name>
  <name xml:lang="id">Globe Behaim</name>
  <name xml:lang="is">Behaim-hnöttur</name>
  <name xml:lang="it">Globo di Behaim</name>
  <name xml:lang="ka">ბეჰაიმის გლობუსი</name>
  <name xml:lang="ko">Behaim 지구본</name>
  <name xml:lang="nl">Globe van Behaim</name>
  <name xml:lang="pl">Globus Behaim</name>
  <name xml:lang="pt">Globo Behaim</name>
  <name xml:lang="pt-BR">Globo de Behaim</name>
  <name xml:lang="ru">Глобус Бехайма</name>
  <name xml:lang="sk">Behaim Globe</name>
  <name xml:lang="sl">Behaim Globe</name>
  <name xml:lang="sv">Behaim-jordgloben</name>
  <name xml:lang="tr">Behaim Küresi</name>
  <name xml:lang="uk">Глобус Бегайма</name>
  <name xml:lang="x-test">xxBehaim Globexx</name>
  <name xml:lang="zh-CN">贝海姆地球仪</name>
  <name xml:lang="zh-TW">倍海姆地球儀</name>
  <summary>Martin Behaim's Erdapfel</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="bg">Земната ябълка на Мартин Бехайм</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ca">Erdapfel de Martin Behaim</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ca-valencia">Erdapfel de Martin Behaim</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="de">Martin Behaim's Erdapfel</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="en-GB">Martin Behaim's Erdapfel</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="eo">Terpomo de Martin Behaim</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="es">El Erdapfel de Martin Behaim</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="eu">Martin Behaim-en «Erdapfel» (patata)</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="fi">Martin Behaimin Erdapfel</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="fr">Martin Behaim Erdapfel</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="gl">Erdapfel de Martin Behaim.</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="id">Erdapfel Martin Behaim</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="is">Erdapfel frá Martin Behaim</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="it">Erdapfel di Martin Behaim</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ka">მარტინ ბეჰაიმის ერდაპფელი</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ko">마르틴 베하임의 Erdapfel</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="nl">De "Erdapfel" van Martin Behaim</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pl">Ziemniak Martina Behaima</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pt">Erdapfel de Martin Behaim</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pt-BR">Erdapfel de Martin Behaim</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ru">«Земное яблоко» Мартина Бехайма</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sk">Martin Behaim Erdapfel</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sl">Martin Behaim's Erdapfel</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sv">Martin Behaims Erdapfel</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="tr">Martin Behaim’in Erdapfel’i</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="uk">Ердапфель Мартіна Бегайма</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="x-test">xxMartin Behaim's Erdapfelxx</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="zh-CN">马丁·贝海姆地球仪</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="zh-TW">馬丁·倍海姆的倍海姆地球儀 (Erdapfel)</summary>
  <description>
    <p>The oldest existent globe of the Earth. Martin Behaim and collaborators created the globe around 1492 at the time of Columbus' first sea travel to the west.</p>
    <p xml:lang="bg">Най-старият съществуващ глобус на Земята. Мартин Бехайм и сътрудници създават глобуса около 1492 г. по време на първото пътуване на Колумб по море на запад.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca">El globus més antic existent de la Terra. Martin Behaim i els col·laboradors van crear el globus al voltant de 1492 en el moment del primer viatge marítim de Colom a l'oest.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">El globus més antic existent de la Terra. Martin Behaim i els col·laboradors van crear el globus al voltant de 1492 en el moment del primer viatge marítim de Colom a l'oest.</p>
    <p xml:lang="de">Der älteste existierende Globus der Erde. Der Globus wurde von Martin Behaim und anderen etwa 1492 erstellt, zu dieser Zeit begann Columbus seine erste Reise nach Westen.</p>
    <p xml:lang="en-GB">The oldest existent globe of the Earth. Martin Behaim and collaborators created the globe around 1492 at the time of Columbus' first sea travel to the west.</p>
    <p xml:lang="eo">La plej antikva ekzistanta globo de la Tero. Martin Behaim kaj kunlaborantoj kreis la globon ĉirkaŭ 1492 je la tempo de la unua marvojaĝo okcidenten de Kolumbo.</p>
    <p xml:lang="es">El globo terráqueo más antiguo que se conserva. Martin Behaim y sus colaboradores crearon el globo hacia 1492, en los tiempos del primer viaje por mar de Colón hacia el oeste.</p>
    <p xml:lang="eu">Existitzen den lurraren globo zaharrena. Martin Behaim eta kolaboratzaileek 1492 inguruan sortu zuten, Colon-en mendebalderako lehenengo bidaiaren garaian.</p>
    <p xml:lang="fi">Vanhin tunnettu karttapallo. Martin Behaim yhteistyökumppaneineen loi sen noin vuonna 1492 samoihin aikoihin Kolumbuksen ensimmäisen länteen suuntautuneen merimatkan kanssa.</p>
    <p xml:lang="fr">Le plus ancien globe existant de la Terre. Martin Behaim et ses collaborateurs ont créé ce globe aux environs de 1492, au moment de la première traversée de Christophe Colomb vers l'Ouest.</p>
    <p xml:lang="gl">O globo terráqueo máis antigo. Martin Behaim e o seu equipo creárono en 1492, no ano da primeira viaxe de Colón por mar ao oeste.</p>
    <p xml:lang="id">Bola dunia tertua yang ada di Bumi. Martin Behaim dan kolaboratornya menciptakan dunia sekitar 1492 pada saat perjalanan laut pertama Columbus ke barat.</p>
    <p xml:lang="is">Elsta hnattlíkanið af Jörðinni sem til er. Martin Behaim og samstarfsmenn hans útbjuggu þetta hnattlíkan árið 1492 á svipuðum tíma og Kólumbus fór fyrst vestur yfir úthafið.</p>
    <p xml:lang="it">Il più antico globo esistente della Terra. Martin Behaim e i suoi collaboratori crearono il globo intorno al 1492 all'epoca del primo viaggio per mare di Colombo verso ovest.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ka">უძველესი არსებული დედამიწის გლობუსი. მარტინ ბეჰაიმმა და თანამშრომლებმა შექმნეს გლობუსი დაახლ. 1492 წელში, როცა კოლუმბი პირველად გაემგზავრა დასავლეთით.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ko">세계에서 가장 오래된 지구본입니다. 마르틴 베하임(Martin Behaim)과 협력자들은 1492년 콜럼버스의 대서양 탐험 시기에 지구본을 만들었습니다.</p>
    <p xml:lang="nl">De oudst bestaande globe van de aarde. Deze werd in 1492 vervaardigd door Martin Behaim en zijn medewerkers, ten tijde van de eerste reis van Columbus naar het westen.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pl">Najstarszy istniejący globus na Ziemi. Martin Behaim i jego współpracownicy stworzyli glob około 1492 w czasie pierwszych podróży morskich Kolumba na zachód.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt">O globo Terrestre mais antigo existente. O Martin Behaim e os seus colaboradores criaram o globo por volta de 1492, na altura da primeira travessia marítima para Oeste por Colombo.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt-BR">O globo mais antigo existente na Terra. Martin Behaim e colaboradores criaram o globo por volta de 1492 na época da primeira viagem marítima de Colombo para o oeste.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ru">Самый старый существующий глобус Земли, был создан под руководством Мартина Бехайма примерно в 1492 году во время первого морского путешествия Колумба на запад.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sk">Najstarší existujúci glóbus Zeme. Martin Behaim a spolupracovníci vytvorili glóbus okolo roku 1492 v čase Kolumbovej plavby na západ.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sl">Najstarejši obstoječi globus sveta. Martin Behaim in sodelavci so ustvarili globus okoli leta 1492 ob času Kolumbovega prvega potovanja na zahod.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sv">Den äldsta kända jordgloben. Martin Behaim och hans medarbetare skapade jordgloben cirka 1492 vid tiden för Columbus första sjöresa västerut.</p>
    <p xml:lang="tr">Dünya’nın var olan en eski küresi. Martin Behaim ve arkadaşları küreyi, Kolomb’un batıya olan ilk deniz yolculuğu sırasında, 1492 civarında yarattılar.</p>
    <p xml:lang="uk">Найдавніший глобус Землі, який зберігся до наших часів. Мартін Бегайм та його помічники створили глобус близько 1492 року, у часи першої подорожі Колумба на захід.</p>
    <p xml:lang="x-test">xxThe oldest existent globe of the Earth. Martin Behaim and collaborators created the globe around 1492 at the time of Columbus' first sea travel to the west.xx</p>
    <p xml:lang="zh-CN">已知最早的地球仪，由马丁·贝海姆以及他的同事制作，时间为 1492 年前后——这是哥伦布首次西向航海的时代。</p>
    <p xml:lang="zh-TW">現存最古老的地球儀。馬丁·倍海姆與合作者在 1492 年哥倫布首次往西出海的時候左右做出了這個地球儀。</p>
  </description>
  <url type="homepage">https://marble.kde.org/</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://bugs.kde.org/enter_bug.cgi?format=guided&amp;product=marble</url>
  <url type="faq">https://techbase.kde.org/Projects/Marble/FAQ</url>
  <url type="help">https://marble.kde.org/support.php</url>
  <url type="donation">https://www.kde.org/community/donations/?app=marble&amp;source=appdata</url>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">org.kde.marble.behaim.desktop</launchable>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>Maps</keyword>
    <keyword>Kirigami</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <developer id="kde.org">
    <name>The KDE Community</name>
    <url>https://kde.org</url>
  </developer>
  <provides>
    <binary>marble-behaim</binary>
  </provides>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1"/>
  <releases>
    <release version="24.08.1" date="2024-09-12"/>
    <release version="24.08.0" date="2024-08-22"/>
    <release version="24.05.2" date="2024-07-04"/>
    <release version="24.05.1" date="2024-06-13"/>
    <release version="24.05.0" date="2024-05-23"/>
    <release version="24.02.2" date="2024-04-11"/>
    <release version="24.02.1" date="2024-03-21"/>
    <release version="24.02.0" date="2024-02-28"/>
    <release version="23.08.5" date="2024-02-15"/>
  </releases>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://cdn.kde.org/screenshots/marble/marble-behaim.png</image>
      <caption>Digital imagery taken directly from the original Behaim globe.</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="bg">Цифрови изображения, взети директно от оригиналния глобус на Behaim.</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ca">Imatges digitals preses directament del globus terraqüi original de Behaim.</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="es">Imágenes digitales obtenidas directamente del globo de Behaim original.</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="fr">Images numériques prises directement à partir du globe original de Behaim.</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="gl">Imaxes dixitais tomadas directamente do globo terráqueo orixinal de Behaim.</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ka">ციფრული გამოსახულებები აღებულია პირდაპირ ორიგინალური ბეჰაიმის გლობუსიდან.</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="nl">Digitaal beeldmateriaal direct genomen van de originele globe van Behaim.</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pl">Cyfrowe obrazy zdjęte bezpośrednio z oryginalnego globusu Behaim.</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sl">Digitalni posnetki, posneti neposredno iz originalnega Behaimovega globusa.</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sv">Digitala bilder tagna direkt från den ursprungliga Behaim-jordgloben.</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="tr">Doğrudan özgün Behaim küresinden alınan sayısal görüntüleme.</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="uk">Цифрові знімки зроблено безпосередньо з оригінального глобуса Бегайма.</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="x-test">xxDigital imagery taken directly from the original Behaim globe.xx</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://cdn.kde.org/screenshots/marble/marble-behaim1.png</image>
      <caption>A (rough) facsimile created by Friedrich Wilhelm Ghillany in 1853.</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="bg">(Грубо) факсимиле, създадено от Фридрих Вилхелм Гилани през 1853 г.</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ca">Un facsímil (aproximat) creat per Friedrich Wilhelm Ghillany el 1853.</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="es">Un facsímil (aproximado) creado por Friedrich Wilhelm Ghillany en 1853.</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="fr">Une copie (Brute) créé par Friedrich Wilhelm Ghillany en 1853.</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="gl">Un facsímile pouco exacto feito por Friedrich Wilhelm Ghillany en 1853.</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ka">(უხეში) ფაქსიმილი, რომელიც შეიქმნა ფრიდრიხ ვილჰელმ გილანის მიერ 1853 წელს.</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="nl">Een (ruwe) facsimile gemaakt door Friedrich Wilhelm Ghillany in 1853.</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pl">(zgrubna) podobizna stworzona przez Friedricha Wilhelma Ghillany w 1853.</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sl">(Grobi) faksimile, ki ga je ustvaril Friedrich Wilhelm Ghillany leta 1853.</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sv">En (grov) faksimil skapad av Friedrich Wilhelm Ghillany 1853.</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="tr">1853 yılında Friedrich Wilhelm Ghillany tarafından oluşturulmuş (kaba) bir faksimile.</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="uk">(Грубе) факсиміле, яке було створено Фрідріхом Вільгельмом Гіланьї у 1853 році.</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="x-test">xxA (rough) facsimile created by Friedrich Wilhelm Ghillany in 1853.xx</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://cdn.kde.org/screenshots/marble/marble-behaim2.png</image>
      <caption>A (rough) facsimile created by Ernest George Ravenstein in 1908.</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="bg">(Грубо) факсимиле, създадено от Ernest George Ravenstei през 1853 г.</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ca">Un facsímil (aproximat) creat per Ernest George Ravenstein el 1908.</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="es">Un facsímil (aproximado) creado por Ernest George Ravenstein en 1908.</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="fr">Une copie (Brute) créé par Ernest George Ravenstein en 1908.</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="gl">Un facsímile pouco exacto feito por Ernest George Ravenstein en 1908.</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ka">(უხეში) ფაქსიმილი, რომელიც შეიქმნა ერნესტ ჯორჯ რავენშტეინის მიერ 1908 წელს.</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="nl">Een (ruwe) facsimile gemaakt door Ernest George Ravenstein in 1908.</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pl">(zgrubna) podobizna stworzona przez Ernesta George Ravensteina w 1908.</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sl">(Grobi) faksimile, ki ga je ustvaril Ernest George Ravenstein leta 1908.</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sv">En (grov) faksimil skapad av Ernest George Ravenstein 1908.</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="tr">1908 yılında Ernest George Ravenstein tarafından oluşturulmuş (kaba) bir faksimile.</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="uk">(Грубе) факсиміле, яке було створено Ернестом Георгом Равенштайном у 1908 році.</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="x-test">xxA (rough) facsimile created by Ernest George Ravenstein in 1908.xx</caption>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
</component>
